Ivan Symchych

Software Engineer from Lviv, Ukraine

Email: ivan.symchych@gmail.com

Github: isymchych

LinkedIn: ivansymchych

SUMMARY

Full-stack software developer with 11 years of experience, seeking interesting projects.

A systems thinker, pragmatic, result-oriented. I enjoy finding simple solutions to complicated problems. Know about clean code, teamwork, documentation, and tests.

Committed to professional growth.

Not interested in gambling, bets, user tracking, or ads industries.

TECHNICAL HIGHLIGHTS

- TypeScript, JavaScript, Rust, Java, SQL, GraphQL
- HTML, CSS, SCSS, CSS-in-JS
- 00P/00D, FP, Design Patterns, SOLID, HTTP, REST
- Linux, Emacs

I'm an expert in TypeScript and JavaScript, love and enjoy Rust, and, earlier in my career, used to code in Java. Last few years I was working primarily with Node.js, React/Redux, GraphQL, REST, HTML, SCSS, CSS-in-JS, and a bit of Angular.

Also, I have experience with HTML5 video streaming and WebRTC.

EXPERIENCE

Consultant at Remit

April 2016 - February 2021

Web Frontend for MaginePro, a video streaming company

MaginePro is a white-label OTT platform. I helped to build the single-page application in React and prerendering server in Node.js. Application is highly customizable via feature flags and scales for multiple partners, which could be configured on the fly.

Also, I was working on a cross-platform video player, Chromecast receiver application, introduced end-to-end tests, and automated internal processes.

React, Redux, Fela, Typescript, Node.js, GraphQL

Calendar application for ThinkTank, the platform for collective intelligence

Single page calendar application for managing events and appointments using REST API in Java. I took part in both frontend and backend development.

Angular, TypeScript, RxJS, SASS, Java, Spring

Consultant at SoftServe

August 2015 - April 2016

Jitsi Meet for Atlassian

I was refactoring and fixing bugs in the Jitsi.org web app, an open-source video conferencing solution. ES6, Babel, Lodash, JQuery

HipChat for Atlassian

I was working on React-based web UI for HipChat, a chat for teams from Atlassian. I took part in refactoring, bugfixing, and writing unit and integration tests.

ES6, React, Lodash, Karma, Selenium

Java/JavaScript developer at Intellias

July 2012 - August 2015

Secure online chat peer.me for Tenios, a German VoIP service provider

Webchat leverages the power of WebRTC, cutting-edge technology which allows browsers to communicate with each other without a server (peer-to-peer), with end-to-end encryption. I was working on JS library which encapsulates core functionality like sending encrypted text messages and files, synchronizing data between clients, establishing group audio and video calls. Also, I took part in the development of SPA UI and backend.

Java, WebSockets, WebRTC, Marionette.js, Tomcat, Jasmine

Web portal and utilities for Tenios, a German VoIP service provider

The web portal is a SPA for customers to manage their phone numbers, routing plans, bills, calls forwarding, etc., and an admin portal to manage customers and internal business processes. The backend was implemented as a REST API. I took part in both frontend and backend development.

Java, Spring, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Marionette.js, Bootstrap

Web portal for RPLab, diagnostic laboratory from Belgium

Web frontend for ETL process on client medical data. As a result, the system also generates per-client reports in HTML or pdf formats. I took part in both frontend and backend development.

Java, Spring, MongoDB, JSP, Stripes, FlyingSaucer, JFreeChart

Java Developer at JSC Kredobank

July 2010 - July 2012

Web services to aggregate and simplify internal business processes

I was working on design, development, bugfixing, and support of internal web services. Also, I built a GUI client in Swing for those web services.

Java, JBoss, SOAP, WSDL, Oracle 11g, Jenkins CI, Gradle

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Applied Mathematics, Ivan Franko National University Of Lviv, Ukraine, 2007 - 2013

LANGUAGES

- Ukrainian Native
- **English** Proficient
- Russian Limited working proficiency

INTERESTS

programming, science fiction & popular science, traveling, hiking, computer games